Two coding agents can edit different files and still implement the same behavior.
Runway compares planned scope before either starts, guards Codex patches, then verifies the final diff.
This is not a fake agent swarm. A public issue produced three human implementations and two duplicate closures.
That proves the failure shape, not agent prevalence. Official Codex guidance separately names conflict risk.
Pricing is airborne. Tax declares the same file, exported symbol, and pricing behavior, so Runway holds it.
Reroute Tax, then reserve it. Checkout stays a caution: an import is evidence, not proof of conflict.
The native Codex hook denies an undeclared patch before execution. The declared Tax file passes.
It guards supported Codex patch tools; it is not a universal write sandbox.
The focused test passes, but a fresh Git audit finds drift, so no handoff exists.
Remove only the drift and verify again. Runway records executed proof before issuing a portable receipt.
Two commands install the skill, hook, and standalone CLI without rebuilding.
The replay fingerprint verifies. Thirty-nine tests cover collisions, concurrency, drift, denial, traversal, and parity.
GPT-5.6 ran through Codex to build and pressure-test the parser, plugin, hook, CLI, protocol, UI, and tests.
Runtime decisions stay deterministic. Runway acts before, during, and after code, with evidence at every boundary.